A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, Administrative papers FA140
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Administrative papers, 1949-1975; 10 Cubic Feet
  - STUDENTS
    - Personal correspondence (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, Special interest: Allen Edmundson James Foch, Peter Wolk.
    - Recruitment of, 1955-1967 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - SUBWAY CONSTRUCTION
    - Citizens' groups, 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Correspondence, releases, reports.
    - Consultants, 1959 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Correspondence, Notes, Memoranda, surveys, figures, technical data.
    - General, 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - New York Transit Authority, 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
      Correspondence, Notes, Memoranda, minutes, map, blueprints, public notices, statement.
    - Publicity, 1963-1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Copies of clippings.
  - Tax exemption, 1955-1968; 2 folders (Box 23, Folder 6-7)
    Correspondence, Notes, Financial tables, government documents.
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1954-1965 1975; 2 folders (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
    Correspondence, Notes, Memoranda, plans, printed matter, tables.
  - Travel, 1957-1974 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Miscellaneous.
  - Treasurer's Office (Dietz, William E.), 1958-1968; 2 folders (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
    Correspondence, Memoranda, investment portfolio, questionnaires, financial data.
  - Vice-President's Office, 1955-1963 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, Memoranda, clipping.
  - Visitors, 1955-1967; 3 folders (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
    Correspondence, Report of 1959 DWB interview, printed matter.
  - Miscellaneous, 1930-1974; 3 boxes or 13 inches, [Box 27 is a 2 1/2-inch box]
    Clippings, reprints, booklets, photographs.
    The material includes one box of clippings from Science, 1954-1968, of articles and Letters to the Editor on science policy issues. Also of note is a collection of 129 reprints and abstract citations of articles by Bronk and his colleagues, 1930-1937. A complete table of contents to the reprints is filed in Box 26, Folder 5.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    This group of papers was delivered to the University Librarian, Mrs. Sonya Mirsky, in January 1981 by Professor Frank Brink, together with some (unprocessed to date) glass slides, and duplicate Bronk reprints.
    File Plan
    Former Classification: I 303
    - Clippings from Science, 1954-1968 (Box 25, Folder 1-13)
      Articles and letters to the Editor on policy issues.
    - Reprints, 1930-1937 (Box 26, Folder 1-4)
      A collection of 129 reprints and abstract citations, 1930-1937. Originally bound in four 2-hole notebooks, with "Contents" listing author (s) and titles only. Includes DWB and other.
    - Table of contents to reprints, with explanatory note [1981] and full journal citations, 1930-1937 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Booklets (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - National Research Fellowships, 1919-1938. Washington, Nat. Res. Council, 1938. Bronk entry, p. 41
      - At Rensselaer, Volume 74, No. 5. 150th anniversary issue. Dec. 1974. Bronk, p. 6 (rec'd Distinguished Service Award
      - Miscellanea, American Philosophical Society, Volume 1, Number 1 [1935]
    - The Rockefeller Foundation, Board of Trustees, Fiftieth anniversary meeting, 1963 April 3 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Statement and photos.
    - "The first academic convocation...", 1959 May 21-22 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Mock-up for printed program.